nest js is a node.js framework for building scalable server-side
Nest js 是一个 node.js 框架，用于使用 typescript构建可扩展的服务器端
applications with typescript it provides a suite of tools that leverage either
应用程序，它提供了一套工具，利用
fastify or express to facilitate rapid development and predictable
fastify 或 express 来促进快速开发和可预测的
readable code it supports rest and graphql apis out of the box or you might
可读代码，它支持开箱即用的 rest 和 graphql api，或者你可以
use it to build a full stack application using the model view controller pattern
使用它来构建一个完整的堆栈应用程序，使用
similar to frameworks like laravel or ruby on rails and it contains a ton
类似于 laravel或 ruby on rails 等框架的模型视图控制器模式，它包含大量
of built-in modules to work with databases
内置模块来处理数据库处理
handle security implement streaming and anything else you can imagine doing in a
安全性实现流以及您可以想象的任何其他事情
server side application nest has its own very powerful command
服务器端应用程序嵌套有自己非常强大的命令
line tool and you can scaffold out a new project with the nest
行工具，您可以使用 nest
new command that provides a code base pre-configured with jest for testing and
new 命令搭建一个新项目，该命令提供了一个预先配置了 jest 的代码库，用于测试并
set up with typescript to help us write more readable and reliable code in the
使用 typescript 进行设置，以帮助我们编写更具可读性和可靠性的代码 在
source directory you'll notice a controller which is a fundamental
源目录中的代码你会注意到一个控制器，它是它负责
building block of the framework it's responsible for handling incoming
的框架的基本构建块 dling传入的
http requests and returning responses back to the
http请求并将响应返回给
client to implement a controller simply add the controller decorator
客户端以实现控制器只需将控制器装饰器添加
to a class then inside the class you can implement methods
到一个类中，然后在类中您可以实现方法
and decorate them with http verbs like git
并使用http动词装饰它们，例如git
post patch put etc by default this will create an http endpoint on the root url
post patch put等默认情况下这将创建一个http 根 url 上的端点，
but you can pass a string to the decorator to
但是您可以将字符串传递给装饰器以
change the route or implement dynamic route parameters in addition
更改路由或实现动态路由参数，此外，
nest provides other decorators to control things like the status code and
嵌套提供其他装饰器来控制状态代码和
headers then in the method itself parameter
标头等内容，然后在方法本身
decorators can be used to access the request parameters or body
中可以使用参数装饰器来访问请求参数或主体
and finally the return value from the method is the response body
，最后来自方法的返回值是
that gets sent back down to the client what's awesome about nest
返回给客户端的响应主体，nest 最棒的地方
is that you can use the cli to automatically generate more controllers
在于，您可以使用 cli自动生成更多控制器
to keep your code organized as it grows in complexity
，以便在代码增长时保持代码井井有条复杂性，
but there's more to nest than just controllers a provider is a class that
但嵌套的不仅仅是控制器，提供者是一个
contains shared logic throughout the entire application
包含共享逻辑的类 hout整个应用程序，
and can be injected as a dependency where needed any class with the
并且可以在需要时作为依赖项注入任何具有
injectable decorator can be injected in the constructor of another class
可注入装饰器的类都可以注入到另一个类的构造函数中
for example a provider can be implemented as a guard to handle
，例如，可以将提供程序实现为处理
role-based user authentication or it might be implemented as a pipe to
基于角色的用户身份验证的守卫，或者可以实现 作为在控制器中
efficiently validate and transform values in a controller
有效验证和转换值的管道
and lastly we have the module decorator which allows code to be organized into
，最后我们有模块装饰器，它允许将代码组织成
smaller chunks where it can be lazy loaded to run
更小的块，可以延迟加载以
faster in serverless environments this has been nest js in 100 seconds if
在无服务器环境中更快地运行，如果你可以在 100 秒内嵌套 js
you want to see more short videos like this
想看更多这样的短视频
make sure to hit the like button and subscribe thanks for watching and i will
记得点赞订阅谢谢收看
see you in the next one
，下期见